Nishal Nandigam

UX Designer

nishal.design nishal.nandigam@gmail.com [616] 328-7352

Summary

Design professional who has expertise in solving customer problems through user-centered design. With a background in engineering, champions solutions that are both meaningful and pragmatic. Excels at taking ideas from concept to wireframe to prototype.

Experience

UX Designer II Amazon

Seattle, WA Jun 2017 - Present Product strategy and design for Amazon's customer service experience.

- Lead designer for Amazon's Customer Service Chatbot. Facilitated design sprints, group ideation, and analysis to inform the future vision of the product. Defined and designed the desktop version of the chatbot. Tested, designed, and launched the chatbot in the Japan and German marketplaces.
- Redesigned the visuals and architecture of the Device and Digital
 Help gateway page to improve the discoverability of common
 problems and handle scalability issues due to the growing number of
 Amazon devices and digital services.
- Designed an intuitive mobile experience where customers can receive technical support for their hardware orders. Validated through guerilla-style customer intercepts.

UX Design Intern Amazon

Seattle, WA May 2016 - Jul 2016 Design strategy for Amazon's post-purchase customer experience.

- Redesigned and validated the experience where customers can track the progress of their shipment. Awarded a U.S. Design Patent for the ornamental design of this tracker.
- Collaborated with Principal Designers to reimagine the design of the progress tracker UI element to reflect the new Amazon visual design style and strategy.

Quality Assurance Intern Amway

Grand Rapids, MI May 2015 - Aug 2015 Software testing for Amway Business Owner web experiences.

- Coordinated with developers and business partners to design and execute test cases to ensure usability of Amway web applications.
 Provided wireframes on how to improve the design of these experiences.
- Redesigned the Amway employee directory to improve usability of the platform. Developed the front-end of the platform in HTML, CSS, Javascript, and Angular.

Education

University of Michigan

Bachelor's of Science in Information, User Experience Design Path Minor in Computer Science Engineering

Ann Arbor, MI Sep 2013 - Apr 2017

Skills

Interaction Design	Prototyping	Visual Design	Web Design
Sketch	Invision Studio	Illustrator	HTML
Balsamiq	Flinto	Photoshop	CSS
Axure	Keynote		Javascript